Omar Vallejo

vallejo.2015@gmail.com 706-575-5987

Profile

Proficiency in planning, staff coordination, collaborating with executives, researching IT solutions and implementing them into systems and infrastructure are my strengths. Offering four-plus years of customer service and technical competence. Constantly dedicated to learning new technology and always striving for the best.

Skills

Technical Skills

- Java Python Visual Basic SQL
- Front-End Web Development Skilled (HTML CSS JavaScript)
- Google Could Platform ExperiencedTroubleshooting Technical Issues
- OS Installations & Upgrades Mac OS Windows OS Ubuntu OS
- Microsoft Office Suite Google Suite

Overall Skills

- Supervisor Experience
- Bilingual English and Spanish
- Great Team Worker
- Project Leader
- Customer Satisfaction Oriented

Work Experience

Columbus State University – Lead PC Repair Technician

04/2017 - Current

Team Leadership: Supervisor of 4 employees including in charge of training new employees, scheduling professional development & discipline. Full network support for all dorms. Strategic planning, inventory management, work lab system optimizations and researching IT solutions providing recommendations for improvement to the university's Technology Department. Hardware and software repair/upgrades and support for students, faculty, and staff.

University Information Technology Services – IT Support Specialist

08/2018 - 12/2018

Provided first contact and incident resolution to customers with hardware, software, and application problems. Includes both customer telephone support as well as electronically submitted requests while providing quality customer support from the university's information technology Help Desk.

Rigdon Park Pool - Manager

Summer of 2017 and 2018

Supervised a ground of 10+ lifeguards and facility maintenance. Assisted patrons with special needs to accommodate for their health issues, arranged private events and kept up with pool chemical levels to make sure they remained at a safe measure. Performed store opening and closing duties, including counting cash drawers, inventory check, facility opening/closing, and safety equipment checks.

Marcos Pizza – Delivery Driver

1/2017 - 3/2018

Assisted customers with placing and picking up orders while in the store. Delivered family and catering orders throughout the shifts. Responsible for assuring customer satisfaction by any way possible. Learned different ways to interact with different types of people.

Columbus State University Student Recreation Center – Customer Service Assistant

08/2016 - 4/2017

Assisted Rec Center guest with weight room needs as well as accommodations if needed. My shifts involved maintaining organization of weights and lifting equipment.

Internships

University Information Technology Services – Project Management Intern

1/2019

Collaborated with the department Project Manager with daily tasks such as retrieving project updates from different departments, recording meeting notes for upcoming projects, and reporting results on projects going on with the PM.

IT Infrastructure and Operations - Networking Department Intern

08/2018 - 12/2018

Responsible for attending device registration issues with the campus. Managed wired and wireless internet access and phone services utilizing Network Sentry and Cisco Clients.

Columbus State University - Cyber Security Inter

1/2018 - 4/2018

Execute tasks such as Audits, Cyber Security Awareness presentations, web page editing, critical document disposal and monitoring user access to the university's network.

Education

Columbus State University – Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

8/2015 - Current

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology. Graduation date of May 2019.

Coursera – From Data to Insights with Google Cloud Platform

1/2019

Coursera Certification in Google Analytics and utilizing Google Cloud Platform to interpret data.